In this exercise on the standard library, you're going to use the OS package and the standard
library to get a little bit more information about our local directory and print out its
contents.
You're also going to use the SIS package to get information about our system, what platform
we're on, and also accept arguments into our Python scripts.
So using the standard library, I'm going to make a new file here.
I'm going to import OS and I'll save that here, just in my pack workshop, all I
live, example.
So oops, I did the wrong thing there.
I want to do a file, save as, want that to be a .py file.
Otherwise, yes, code doesn't know.
Okay, so import OS, what is OS in the standard library, do what it's it for?
It's damn cool.
Collaborating system functions.
Operating system functions.
So I can say my folder equals, and I can use the OS module to get the CWD, CW stands
for current working directory.
And I can print out, here are the files in, let me make that an F string, let's say, my
folder.
So this is going to be the name of the folder.
Let me quickly run this, not sorry, not start Reball, and it's select run Python file
in terminal.
And because I started a new Reball session in this terminal that VS code doesn't really
know to track, I'm going to have to hit Ctrl C to exit the Reball, and then I should
be able to run my file in the terminal.
So here's the full path.
And then if I wanted to loop through this folder, I can say, with OS dot scan directory,
my folder as folder.
And we haven't seen this with syntax just yet, but what this is is a context manager.
And after the code in this block is done running, the context manager is automatically
going to do some code cleanup.
So generally a good idea when we're working with files, because the system will want
to close the handles to those files.
So you'll also see this with syntax when working with or writing 2 files.
OK, so and using the as label, we're going to get the contents of scanning the directory
and assign it to folder.
So I can say for entry in folder, print out an aftering of the name of the entry.
And if I run this in my terminal, you'll see all of the files here, the top level, files
in that directory.
This is another useful library.
It's going to give you some access to variables and functions used or maintained by the Python
interpreter.
So I'm going to make a new file here.
And I'm going to save it as this example dot pui.
I'm going to import this.
And there's a variable called systemrv that is always set to the command line arguments used
to run this script.
So I can say, print out, we received these arguments.
And I'm just going to print them out.
And then I can also say, I'm going to print out an aftering and say, we're currently running
on a and use sys.clapform, which will be set to the OS that you're using machine.
OK, so if I run this in the terminal, I'll see that we received these arguments.
And there's already one value in this list, even though we didn't pass anything in.
So running that again with that providing the full path, what is this first argument?
This is the file.
This is the file name.
So sys.rgv is never empty.
The zero with element is always the name of the file.
And after that, I can pass in whatever values I want.
And we'll see that we receive these arguments.
And each of those space-separated arguments gets passed into sys.rgv.
Notice that even though I passed in some integers here, the arguments are always strings.
OK, using pipi.
If we don't want to open the website, and we kind of want to do a little bit of exploration,
pipi has a really helpful search method.
So I could say a python, pip is the tool associated with pipi, and I can say pip search requests.
And this will go and get me a list of the packages that have requests in the name.
If I want to install a package, I could say python, pip, and install requests.
And I already have it installed, but then it'll go ahead and do that.